(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-31T09:04:30.956710",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
黄金のシンボル鳴らすように
Like ringing a golden symbol,
鳴くのはお日様
The sun is singing out.
「一緒においで 木々の宴に」
"Come join us for a banquet in the trees,"
耳を 澄ませましょう
Let's listen closely.
シャボンの雲で顔を洗い
Washing our faces with bubble clouds,
そよそや風と散歩
Taking a walk in the gentle breeze.
「大丈夫きっと...」羽根になるココロ
"We'll be okay, I'm sure..." Our hearts become wings,
ヒカリへと 放してごらん
Try releasing them toward the light.
虹を結んで空のリボン
A ribbon in the sky connecting rainbows,
君の笑顔へ贈り物よ
A gift for your smile.
願いをかけましょう夢日和
Let's make a wish on this dream-weather day,
明日また しあわせで あるように
Hoping tomorrow will be happy once again.
雲の綿菓子摘まれては
Picking cotton candy from the clouds,
ひと休みの草原
A resting place in the meadow.
「風はどこへ 帰っていくの?」
"Where does the wind go back to?"
鳥に 尋ねましょう
Let's ask the birds.
夕日のレース肩にかけて
With the lace of the sunset on our shoulders,
伸びている影と駆けっこ
Playing tag with our stretching shadows.
「見守ってるずっと...」光る宵月の
"I'll always watch over you..." The shining moon,
優しさに 包まれてごらん
Enveloping us in its tenderness.
星を並べて空のボタン
Lining up stars like buttons in the sky,
夜のカーテンを留めてあげる
Fastening the curtain of night.
明日も逢えるよ夢日和
We can meet tomorrow too, on this dream-weather day,
その笑顔 忘れてい ないなら
If you haven't forgotten that smile.
「大丈夫きっと...」羽根になるココロ
"We'll be okay, I'm sure..." Our hearts become wings,
ヒカリへと 放してごらん
Try releasing them toward the light.
虹を結んで空のリボン
A ribbon in the sky connecting rainbows,
君の笑顔へ贈り物よ
A gift for your smile.
願いをかけましょう夢日和
Let's make a wish on this dream-weather day,
明日また しあわせで あるように
Hoping tomorrow will be happy once again.
裏路地の真中で
Right in the middle of the back alley,
慣れない景色と好かない匂いに
Surrounded by unfamiliar scenery and scents,
私は覆われて
I am covered over,
染まっていくんでしょう
And dyed by it all, I suppose.
私は怖がりで
I'm a coward,
知らないことには手を付けず
Never touching things I don't know,
誰かがやってきて
Waiting until someone else comes along
毒味をするまで待っていた
To taste-test it first.
することは単純で
What I do is simple:
マニュアル通りの生活を
Living a life straight by the manual,
来る日も淡々と
Passing each day unremarkably.
過ごしていた
Just getting by.
そう優しさ そう優しさ
Oh, how kind, oh, how kind—
昨日の私もこうだった
Yesterday's me was just like this.
そう優しさ そう優しさ
Oh, how kind, oh, how kind.
弱い音を吐いている
Complaining and whining,
薄っぺらい人間です
I'm a shallow human being.
一歩前に出るのはやめときます
I'll refrain from stepping forward,
絡まれたくないからさ
Because I don't want any trouble.
描きたい想像に
My ideal imagination
現実味がないからさ
Lacks any sense of reality,
近づけないよう生きていきます
So I'll live keeping my distance,
明日も同じように過ごしておきます
And spend tomorrow just the same.
路地裏の真中で
Right in the middle of the back alley,
いつもの夕日を薄目で眺めて
Gazing squint-eyed at the usual sunset,
胸の内で呟いた
I muttered within my chest:
「いつまで続くだろう」
"How long will this last?"
そう優しさ そう優しさ
Oh, how kind, oh, how kind—
昨日も夕飯これだった
Yesterday's dinner was this too.
そう優しさ そう優しさ
Oh, how kind, oh, how kind.
臆病で切りが悪い
Cowardly and indecisive,
口なし人間です
A spineless human being.
一歩後ろに下がって逃げときます
I'll take a step back and run away,
目立ちたくなんかないからさ
Because I don't want to stand out at all.
描きたい想像に
My ideal imagination
現実味がないからさ
Lacks any sense of reality,
近づけないよう生きていきます
So I'll live keeping my distance,
明日も同じように少しどきます
And spend tomorrow stepping slightly aside.
弱い音を吐いている
Complaining and whining,
薄っぺらい人間です
I'm a shallow human being.
一歩前に出るのはやめときます
I'll refrain from stepping forward,
絡まれたくないからさ
Because I don't want any trouble.
ため息ばっかでさ
Just sighing all the time,
吸う息足りないの
Not getting enough breath to inhale—
きっとそう上手くはいかないけどさ
I'm sure it won't go all that well, but
試しにちゃんと生きてみよう
Let's try properly living for a change.
鉄の弾が 正義の証明
Iron bullets are the proof of justice,
貫けば 英雄に近づいた
Piercing through brought me closer to being a hero.
その目を閉じて 触れてみれば
Close your eyes and reach out to touch—
鉄の弾が 正義の証明
A bullet of iron is proof of justice,
貫けば 英雄に近づいた
if you pierce through, you'd be close to a hero.
その目を閉じて 触れてみれば
If you close your eyes and touch it,
同じ形 同じ体温の悪魔
an evil with the same shape and body temperature.
僕はダメで あいつはいいの?
"I'm no good, but why is he fine?"
そこに壁が あっただけなのに
Even though there was just a wall there,
生まれてしまった 運命嘆くな
I was born—don't lament fate.
僕らはみんな 自由なんだから
Because we are all free.
鳥のように 羽があれば
If we had wings like birds,
どこへだって 行けるけど
we could go anywhere we wanted, but—
帰る場所が なければ きっとどこへも行けない
if we have nowhere to return to, we can't go anywhere.
ただただ 生きるのは嫌だ
I hate just merely living.
世界は 残酷だ それでも 君を愛すよ
This world is cruel, but even so, I'll love you.
何を 犠牲にしても それでも 君を守るよ
No matter what I sacrifice, I'll still protect you.
間違いだとしても 疑ったりしない
Even if it's a mistake, I won't doubt it.
正しさとは 自分のことを強く信じることだ
Righteousness is strongly believing in oneself.
鉄の雨が 降り散る情景
A shower of iron falling and scattering,
テレビの中 映画に見えたんだ
it looked like a movie inside the TV.
戦争なんて 愚かな凶暴
War is such a foolish brutality.
関係ない 知らない国の話
A story of an unknown country we have nothing to do with.
それならなんで あいつに憎んで 黒い気持ち 隠しきれない
Then why hate him and hide these dark feelings?
理由だって 説明だって できやしないんだ
Even explanation is something I can't do.
僕らはなんて 矛盾ばっかなんだ
We are nothing but contradictions.
この言葉も 訳されれば
Even if these words are misinterpreted,
本当の意味は 伝わらない
their true meaning won't get across.
信じるのは その目を開いて 触れた世界だけ
What to believe is the world you touched with your eyes open.
ただただ 生きるのは嫌だ
I hate just merely living.
世界は 残酷だ それでも 君を愛すよ
This world is cruel, but even so, I'll love you.
何を 犠牲にしても それでも 君を守るよ
No matter what I sacrifice, I'll still protect you.
選んだ人の影 捨てたものの屍
The shadows of chosen people, the corpses of discarded things—
気づいたんだ 自分の中 育つのは悪魔の子
I realized that deep inside myself, an evil child grows.
正義の裏 犠牲の中 ここには悪魔の子
Behind the righteousness, inside the sacrifice, here is an evil child.
always going 何千回 何万回 膝をついても
Always going, no matter how many thousands or millions of times I fall to my knees,
最大級 i love you で立ち上がれるから
I can get back up with a max-level "I love you,"
飛びっきり オーバーな ty
a surprisingly over-the-top S.T.Y.!
デボボだから ジャストに噛み合う パズルピース
Even if we're mismatched, we're puzzle pieces that just fit together.
繋ぎたい 繋ぎたい
I want to connect, I want to connect,
届かない 言葉も
even words that won't reach
いつかは 誰かの 何かに 成りたいから
will someday become someone's something.
crazy no lazy 夢の中 夢を見せて
Crazy, no lazy—let me see dreams within a dream.
always going 何千回 何万回 迷い込んでも
Always going, no matter how many thousands or millions of times I get lost in doubt,
最大級 i love you な君がいるから
because you're here with a max-level "I love you,"
全身 スペシャルな ty
a whole-hearted special S.T.Y.!
常世の闇に囚われたまま
Trapped in the eternal darkness,
奏でる悲鳴を 聴かせて
play out your screams for me...
さあ 爪を磨いたら まだ 子供のような あなたのために
Now, once you've sharpened your claws, for you, still like a child,
ああ 試されたいなら その 愚かな手に 手錠をかけて
Ah, if you wish to be tested, put handcuffs on those foolish hands.
背中には 君という羽で
On my back, with wings named you,
チクタク追い越して
Chasing past the ticking clock,
いつも どっか乾いた初層が
always somewhere dry at the start,
隣で走る 君と
running beside you,
降り出す 雨 二人
rain starting to fall on the two of us.
君の色が 私を塗り替えて
Your color repaints over me,
壊れかけの 音で響くから
echoing with a broken sound,
音沙汰無しの 続きをまだ描きたいんだよ
and I still want to draw the continuation with no word from you.
パレード パレード 連れて行くよ
Parade, parade, I'll take you along!
きっと 何全回何万回
Surely, thousands and tens of thousands of times,
迷い込んだとしても
even if we get lost,
Always going...
何全回何万回
thousands and tens of thousands of times,
迷い込んでも 最大級I love youな君がいるから
even if we get lost, because you're here with maximum "I love you".
個人スペシャルのサンキュー それでもってラッキー
A personal special thank you, and still lucky,
運命も宿命も手繰り寄せて
pulling fate and destiny closer,
もうバイバイも涙も忘れないよ
I won't forget the goodbyes or the tears anymore.
飛べなかった 私の
The me who couldn't fly,
この背中には 君という羽で
on this back of mine, with wings named you,
Wow wow...
Woah...
描いた未来の景色がここにある
The scenery of the future I drew is right here.
弱さも抱きしめていくから
Embracing even my weaknesses as I go,
広げた翼が輝いていく
my spread wings are shining brightly.
飛び立てる？ 私と
"Can you take flight with me?"
等身大の私を映していたい
I want to reflect my true self as I am.
ただ望む瞬間衝動になってんだ
It just became an instantaneous impulse of desire.
「くだらない」とか
Stuff like "how pointless"
曇りきってきた目を拭いて
wiping away my clouded eyes,
可能性だって夢を見てみたいのに
even though I want to dream of possibilities.
ずっとわかっていたんだけれど
I've known it all along,
言葉は打ってる 対象に
but the words are aimed at the target.
「大袈裟だな」なんて思ってるんでしょ？
You must be thinking, "That's an exaggeration, right?"
ずっと黙っていたんだけれど
I've kept quiet all this time,
心ってやっぱ正直だ
but the heart is honest after all.
打ち込まれた「色」を感じた気がして
I felt like I sensed the "color" shot into me.
「ここだよ」響かせて
Making "Here it is" resonate,
掲げたこの腕 わかんないんでしょ？
raising this arm—you don't get it, do you?
明かりになっていく
Becoming the light.
何度も盗まれて 取り戻した
Stolen countless times, and won back,
意志の傷跡に誓った
I swore upon the scars of my will.
失敗、後悔はない？
No failures, no regrets?
ため息の音がしている
The sound of a sigh is echoing.
現状に不安はない？
Any anxiety about the current state?
飲み込んだ 浸ってたんだ
I swallowed it down and was immersed in it.
ああ 忘れないように 金環際
Ah, so I won't forget, the ring of fire,
もう汚されないように
so it won't be tainted anymore.
もっと笑っていたいんだもの
I just want to smile more.
大人になってく代償に
As compensation for growing up.
繰り戻した 日々の傷口に
Into the wound of the rewound days...
地球は止まった
The Earth stopped.
心音を響かせて
Let my heartbeat echo...
ずっと…
Forever...
ここだよ響かせて 掲げたこの腕で
Right here, let it echo, with these raised arms,
まだマイペースで ぎりぎり足掻き続けていく
still at my own pace, struggling on by the skin of my teeth.
何度も 盗まれた 照りかえした 日々の傷跡に
Countless times, stolen, reflecting upon the scars of those days...
誓った
I swore.
はーい！
Hi there!
はー、皆さん！
Haah, everyone!
というわけで、本日は、えー、常闇トワ生誕祭2025にお越しくださりありがとうございます！
So, thank you all so much for coming to Tokoyami Towa's Birthday Festival 2025 today!
こえっぴー！ ホロライブ生誕の常闇トワ様です！イエーイ！
Koeppi! It's Hololive's birthday girl, Tokoyami Towa! Yay!
ちょっと水飲んでもいいですか？
Can I drink some water for a second?
ちょっと水もらっていいですか。少々…さらさら、さら、ちょっと、
Can I get some water? Just a moment...
あ、すみませんね、ちょっと、あ、水、あそこ、どこに行ってもカメラが映るのよ
Oh, sorry about that. Water... no matter where I go, the camera catches me.
はあ、水欲し。
Ah, I wanted water.
ということで、皆さん、今日はライブにお越しいただきありがとうございます！3Dライブをやらせていただいております。
So everyone, thank you so much for coming to the live today! We're doing a 3D live.
ということで、えー、早速なんですけれども、ありがと！みんなおめでとう！ありがと！ありがと！見えてますよ。
So, without further ado—thank you! Congrats everyone! Thank you! Thank you! I can see you all.
はい、早速なんですけれどもね、今回の配信のハッシュタグは、こちら！
Yes, and right away, the hashtag for today's stream is right here!
#常闇トワ生誕祭2025 ということでね、こちらのね、Xでたくさんポストをしていただければなと思います！
#TokoyamiTowaBirthday2025 — please make lots of posts on X with this!
スクリーンショットとかね、
Screenshots and...
感想もいっぱいいただけたら嬉しいです。
I'd be so happy to receive lots of your thoughts and impressions too.
スクショはね、もしもしね、えー、素敵なのがあったら、ちょっとパク、パク、パクるというか、
And screenshots... if there are any nice ones, I might "steal"—borrow them...
あの拝借というか、なんというか、なんて言うんですかね？あの、勝手にこれ使っちゃおうみたいな感じで使って、
or borrow them, or whatever you call it? Like, "I'll just use this without asking,"
あのこれを終わったあとにポストするかもしれないんですけども、そのために撮っといてくれたらなみたいな、
and maybe post them after it's over, so if you could take them for that purpose...
あの手伝ってくれたらなと
if you could help me out with that,
思います。よろしくお願いいたします！フレームワークの共有ね！言い方ね、フレームワークの共有だから！
I'd appreciate it. Thank you! It's "sharing the framework"! Watch your wording, it's sharing the framework!
そしてね、え、本日はライブだけじゃなくて、いろんなね発表も、え、したいと思いますので、最後まで見ていてくれたら嬉しいです！
And also, today isn't just a live; we'll also have various announcements, so I hope you'll watch all the way to the end!
ここまでなんですけれども、え、1曲目にね、Wabakaさんの楽曲の「弱ね吐き」、2曲目に、江口愛さんの、「悪魔の子」、そしてトワのオリジナル曲の「STY」と「プレゼントデイ」を歌わさせていただきました。ありがとうございます！
Up to this point, we sang Wabaka's song "Yowanehaki" for the first song, Eguchi Ai's "Akuma no Ko" for the second, and Towa's original songs "STY" and "Present Day". Thank you!
今日のね、配信のオープニングは、え、プレゼントデイのイントロを使ってます！テンション上がるよね！
Today's stream opening uses the intro of "Present Day"! Gets you pumped, right?
はい、この曲かっこいい。かっこいいけどイントロが難しいんでいっつもあの皆さんに聞こえないとこでクリック音をつけてもらってます。
Yeah, this song is cool. It's cool, but the intro is difficult, so I always have them add a click track where you guys can't hear it.
恥ずかしいんですけども、すごい難しいから！はい。
It's embarrassing, but because it's super difficult! Yeah.
そしてね、え、今日はね、ちょっともりもりに関情報がもりもりなんだけど、歌もね、みんなにお届けしたいと思うので1回ここでちょっと落ち着いて、
And, um, today—information is packed, super packed, but I also want to deliver songs to everyone, so let's calm down a bit here,
え、次の曲にね、え、行きたいと思います！いっぱいね、え、発表がしたいと思うので、あの、待っていてください！
and move on to the next song! I want to make lots of announcements, so please wait for them!
はい、ということで次の曲、え、オリジナル楽曲の続きになります。え、聞いてください、「My Abyss」。
Alright, so for the next song, it continues with my original songs. Please listen: "My Abyss".
堕ちていくdebris
Sinking debris...
忘れて混ざり合うfall down
Forgetting and mingling, fall down...
眠れない夜この気持ちはもう溶けて消えていく
On sleepless nights, this feeling is already melting away.
からまった導火線には火花近づけplay on
To the tangled fuse, bring the spark closer, play on...
つまらないデイズももう散々ね！
Even boring days are already plenty annoying!
奇跡願っているだけの人生
A life of just wishing for miracles
Watch me do...
呪術秘中トリック無しのマジック
Magic without tricks, amidst sorcery's secrets
I wanna be free! だってまだ不真面目
I wanna be free! 'Cause I'm still not serious
(The party ain’t started)
Heyタクシー ちょっと宇宙まで
Hey taxi, let's head up to space
おどりましょ
and dance!
目が合うのは誰？
Who is it that our eyes meet?
深い闇へ落ちてく
Falling into the deep darkness
手伸ばせ あなたまで届きますように
Reach out, hoping it reaches even you
Climbing
先には ここまでも広がるジ・アビス
Ahead lies the abyss that spreads even here
掴みかけて あなたの手をこじ開けますように
Grasping, hoping to pry open your hands
I wish
光射す 先には ここまでも広がるジ・アビス
Beyond the shining light lies the abyss that spreads even here
彷徨っていた In the backroom
Wandering in the backroom
でも欲しいの Moon もたもたぬるいGoodもFreeだ
But what I want is the Moon, even sluggish, tepid good and free are fine
全部濁った Everywhere
Everything is muddied everywhere
Hey This is Underground 悪ふざけなら私のよ
Hey this is underground, if it's mischievous fun, it's mine
我慢しなくてもいいんじゃない？もうこっちにおいで
Isn't it okay not to hold back anymore? Come over here
尖らせた爪で
With sharpened claws
握ったら Make you evil
Grasping it, I'll make you evil
音立てずに 触れて 掴みかけて
Making no sound, touching, trying to grasp
あなたはどうしたい？ I wanna be my master
What do you want to do? I wanna be my master
今夜すべて忘れて Wake up to my pattern
Tonight, forget everything, wake up to my pattern
歌歌い 沈んでゆく ダーティーバリュー
Singing, sinking down, dirty value
統べ統べ 忘れて 混ざり合う Who am I?
Completely forgetting, blending together, who am I?
メメメ眩暈夜 この気持ちはもう
Dizzy, dazzling night, this feeling is already...
ルルル 絡まって 溶かすには 輪郭近づけてよ くっつけて
Rururu, entangling, to melt them, bring the outlines close and press them together
リンディカには 恋焦がれて
To the Lindica, yearning with love
あなたはどうしたい？ I wanna be a sage
What do you want to do? I wanna be a sage
今夜 一晩中 踊りましょ
Tonight, all night long, let's dance!
目が合うのは誰？
Who is it that our eyes meet?
深い闇へ落ちてく
Falling into the deep darkness
駆け出せ この闇から 逃げ出せるように
Run out, hoping to escape from this darkness
Climbing
先には あなたの手を 掴めたなら
Ahead, if I could only grasp your hand
I wish
光射す 先には ここまでも広がるジ・アビス
Beyond the shining light lies the abyss that spreads even here
どこまでも深く どこまでも墜ちていく ジ・アビス
Deeper and deeper, falling endlessly into the abyss
落ちていく
Falling down
昔々 悪魔の娘が顔のない国に作ったとさ
Once upon a time, a devil's daughter created a nation without faces
やがて多くの人々が集い賑わった
Before long, many people gathered and bustled
娘はあいたく喜び深く浸てたが
The daughter rejoiced deeply and immersed herself, but
顔のない人々は 自ら神を名乗り始めた
The faceless people began calling themselves gods
おお 直球 直球 でも 直球 直球
Oh, straight pitch, straight pitch, but straight pitch, straight pitch
ゾッと ゾッと
Terrifying, terrifying
考えて 神様の言う通り
Think about it, just as God says
曇物は甘い 程遠い子供たちの邪気よ
Clouds are sweet, the malice of children far away
あれが欲しい これが欲しい 暴れてはただ拗ねる
I want that, I want this, throwing tantrums and just pouting
バズビバザヴァ さあ ソロはからせとこ
Buzibuzaba, now let's make the solo resound
またたちまちあっという間に悪魔に みるみる悪魔に
In the blink of an eye, turning right into demons before our eyes
さあ烈日な朝日を浴びせ 奇跡をごらんあれ バズビ バズビ Oh Yeah!
Now bathe in the scorching morning sun and witness the miracle, Buzibi Buzibi Oh Yeah!
骨茎にクラクラするほど 色気付くわ
Growing so seductive it makes your bones spin
目に触れ 磁気の中で 悶えちゃおう 魔界から歌い踊り出せる
Touching your eyes, let's writhe in the magnetism, singing and dancing out from the underworld
やたりあたり ええ!
Hit or miss, eh!
邪魔くない? 混ぜてない? 声合わせて唱えましょう
Isn't it a nuisance? Aren't we mixing? Let's chant together with our voices aligned
バズビバザヴァ！
Buzibuzaba!
7 calling us time
どしたん？
What's wrong?
深くファナティック
Deeply fanatical
浸すロマンティック
Immersing romantic
「ベきだ」とかノー サンキュー です
Saying "You must" is a no thank you
個人的な感想とか
Personal impressions and such
悪魔的な妄想とか
Demonic delusions and such
は？マジ終わってるんですけど
Huh? Seriously, it's already over
listen up
瞬く間にあっという間に悪魔に
In the blink of an eye, instantly into a devil
見る見る悪魔に
Watching and watching into a devil
瞬く間にあっという間に悪魔に
In the blink of an eye, instantly into a devil
あくまで悪魔に
To the very end, a devil
guilty！ duty！
Guilty! Duty!
stupid！ majesty！
Stupid! Majesty!
バズビバザヴ バズビバザヴ order！
Buzz bibazav Buzz bibazav order!
ああ
Ah...
反吐が出ちゃうぐらいグルグルセール
Spinning enough to make me vomit
ブランドニュー邪教ならここは聖地 崇めて
If it's a brand-new evil cult, this is a sacred place, worship it
私に集え 集え合図は666
Gather, gather to me, the signal is 666
「侮を！お慈悲を！」って泣いていいんじゃない？
Isn't it okay to cry out, "Have mercy! Have pity!"?
昔々悪魔の娘が顔のない国作ったとさ やがて多くのヒトビトが集い賑わった
Once upon a time, a devil's daughter created a faceless land, and soon many people gathered and bustled.
魔法歌い踊り
Singing, dancing magic
揺たり揺たり
Swaying, swaying
こいつってヤバくない？
Isn't this dangerous?
コワくない？ 声合わせ唱えましょう
Isn't it scary? Let's voice our chants together
バズビバザヴ！響かす song
Buzz bibazav! Resounding song
聖母降臨ダンスタイム
Holy mother advent dance time
ちょっと
Wait...
ゼボコーリングダンスタイム
Sebo calling dance time
心の奥で、残響がする。
An echo reverberates in the depths of the heart.
それは、
That is,
過去を超えるための進化か。深い底へ潜る 魂の奥底へ潜る 進化か。
Evolution to surpass the past, diving into the deep abyss of the soul.
己の存在を証明する真価か。
The true value proving one's existence.
揺らぎ、信じ、見つけ出した 心の芯。
Wavering, believing, finding the core of the heart.
常闇を裂き、偽りのノイズを消し去って、
Tearing through the eternal darkness, erasing false noise,
いま、真実の歌声を
Now, the voice of truth
2ndアルバム 発売決定
2nd Album Release Confirmed
響き渡る、始まりの『SHIN』
Resonating, the beginning "SHIN"
はい！
Yes!
ということで、皆さん！常闇トワセカンドアルバム「SHIN」の発表が、発表じゃねえわ、発売が決定しましたー！
So everyone! Tokoyami Towa's 2nd album "SHIN" announcement—ah, not announcement, release has been confirmed!
はーい！ありがとうございます！待たせました！
Yay! Thank you very much! Kept you waiting!
はい、今回のジャケット写真は、花澤あきらさんに描き下ろししていただきましたー！ めっちゃかっこいいでしょこれ！
Yes, this time's jacket illustration was drawn for us by Akira Hanazawa! Isn't this super cool?!
鎖引きちぎってね、一緒なんだって。話しよ。
Ripping the chains apart, we're together, she said. Let's talk about it.
はい！そしてね、10月8日トワの日ですね！これね、ちょっと指定、指定させていただきました！
Yes! And you know, October 8th is Towa's Day! We requested this date!
10月8日から今回もファーストに続き全国流通での発売となっております！ はい、ありがとうございます！
Starting October 8th, this one will also be released nationwide just like the first! Yes, thank you very much!
豪華作家陣の皆様に書き下ろしていただいた新曲がたくさん収録されております！
Many new songs written by gorgeous creators are included!
ジャケットいいでしょ？もっと言って。すごい素敵なジャケット描いてくれました。本当嬉しいです。
Isn't the jacket good? Tell me more. They drew such a wonderful jacket. I'm really happy.
そしてね、セカンドアルバムなんですけれども完全生産限定版と通常版の2種類をご用意しております。
And, regarding the 2nd album, we have two versions available: the Complete Limited Edition and the Regular Edition.
まず完全生産限定版はこちらじゃーん！あ、こっちだった。
First, the Complete Limited Edition is here, ta-da! Ah, it was this way.
外箱がね、超豪華スリーブボックスになっております！へい、へいだって。はい、かなた描いて。へい。
The outer box is a super gorgeous sleeve box! "Hey, hey," it says. Yes, Kanata drawn. Hey.
そして中身はこちら！アクリルブロックキーホルダーやアナザージャケットカード、サイン入りオリジナルグッズなどが当たる！
And the contents are here! Acrylic block keychain, another jacket card, signed original goods and more to be won!
抽選応募券！6種類のMVカットステッカーセット、あとはねホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームPRカードの常闇トワなどなど豪華特典がたくさん入っております！
Lottery application ticket! 6 types of MV cut sticker sets, and also Hololive Official Card Game PR card of Tokoyami Towa and many other gorgeous bonuses are included!
ボックスなんですけれども、通常のCDよりもちょっとひと回りふた回りぐらい大きい、あの本当に限定版のその、飾る用というかね、そういう感じのプレミアム感が付いて
Regarding the box, it's a bit larger, about one or two sizes bigger than a regular CD, it has a premium feel meant for display for the limited edition...
ボックスの、えー、限定盤となっております。
...box, um, as a limited edition.
はい、そしてね、アナザージャケットカードにはランダムでトワのね、直筆サインが入っております！
Yes, and the another jacket cards will randomly feature my handwritten signature!
はい、えー、そしてね、プレゼントキャンペーン商品のラインナップはこちらです。
Yes, um, and here is the lineup for the present campaign prizes.
このね、キービジュアル、キービジュアルっていうの？これ違うか。えー、ライブのジャケ写？
This key visual—is it called a key visual? Or is this different? Um, jacket photo for the live?
ジャケ写？ジャケ写か、ジャケット写真を使ったTシャツとか、ポスターとか、缶バッチがね、えーできてます。
Jacket photo? Jacket photo, right? T-shirts, posters, and button badges using jacket photos have been made.
かっこいいでしょ？はい！かっこいいの欲しいよね？トワも、トワも欲しい、ごめんけど。
Isn't it cool? Yes! You want something cool, right? Towa wants it too, sorry though.
だから、トワがじゃあ1枚取るから、2名様と、9名様とか
So, since Towa will take one, two winners, and nine winners—
嘘ですよ、嘘嘘！皆さん、皆さんのためにちゃんとありますから！はい！
Just kidding, kidding, kidding! There are definitely prizes for everyone! Yes!
そしてね、続いて通常盤はこちらです。
And now, here is the regular edition.
はい、顔のね、ちょっとアップがボーンって入ったような、かっこいい、もう、目もう、釘付けでしょ、トワの顔に。
Yes, with a close-up of my face popping right out, super cool, your eyes will be glued to Towa's face.
はい、こちらのね、え、デザインとなっておりまして、通常盤にはスマホサイズのジャケットイラストステッカーが入っております。
Yes, this is the design, and the regular edition includes a smartphone-sized jacket illustration sticker.
え、こちらのね、かっこいいジャケ写の、え、ステッカー、スマホに貼ったり、PCに貼ったり、えー何ですか、レバーレスとかに貼ったりとか、ね、アゲココに貼ったりとかしてもらえれば嬉しいですと。はい！
Um, you can put this cool jacket photo sticker on your smartphone, PC, leverless controller, or Agkoko, and I'd be happy if you do! Yes!
さて、今回のアルバムに楽曲 a書き下ろしてくださった作家陣の皆様はこちらです！
Now, here are the creators who wrote the songs for this album!
ボーン！実はね、さっき、え、わぬかさんの「弱音ハキ」だとか、えー、樋口愛さんの「悪魔の子」だとか歌ってるけど、なんと！書いてくれてるんですよ！書き下ろしてもらえましたー！
Boom! Earlier, I sang Wanuka's "Yowane Haki" and Ai Higuchi's "Akuma no Ko," but guess what! They wrote songs for me!
実は伏線だったっていうね、はい、そういう感じで、ちょっと組み合わせていただきました。
It was actually foreshadowing, yes, so we put it together like that.
イエーイ！
Yay!
はい、そうなんです。あとね、まあ色々、まあ見てびっくりすることもあると思うんですけども、あ、この前の「My Abyss」が収録されてたりとか、「BuzzBbazzB」があったりとか、しておりますと。はい！
Yes, that's right. Also, there are various things that might surprise you, like "My Abyss" being included or "BuzzBbazzB" being there. Yes!
えー、どの楽曲もすごいステキに仕上がりなんでね、楽しみにしていただければと思います。はい！
Um, all the songs turned out wonderfully, so I hope you look forward to them. Yes!
そして、各店舗別の特典はこちら、ボーン！
And here are the store-specific bonuses, boom!
もう、いろんな種類がいっぱいあるからね、どの特典も欲しくなると思うんですけども、全部買ってもよし、選んで買ってもよしということで、
There are so many different types, so you'll probably want all the bonuses, but it's totally fine to buy all of them or choose one.
え、1つずつ紹介したいところを、これを全部紹介するとたぶん5年ぐらい経つんでね、自分で見てくださいと、完全生産限定盤も通常盤も絶対手に入れてくださいと。
If I introduce every single one, it'll take about 5 years, so check them out yourself, and make sure to get both editions!
そして、こちらはね、本日21時から発売開始なんですが、が、が、
And these go on sale tonight at 9 PM, but, but, but...
ホロライブ公式ECでは、なんと、この配信中に、えっと、え、なんですが、が、が、なんとホロライブ公式ECでは編集点、この配信中にCDが買えるようになるかも？なんか出てきてポチって押せたりする？か、か、か、か、も？
Hololive official EC—wait, during this stream, CD purchases might become available? M-m-m-maybe?
ということで、楽しみに待っていてくださーい！はい！
So please look forward to it! Yes!
え、この後ですね、そして、次の曲はなんとこの後からね、この後、セカンドアルバムから1曲、新曲を披露します！
And for the next song, we will debut a brand-new track from the second album right after this!
えー、ナールセさん、え、GTAとかでねお世話になってるナールセ兄貴っすね、お兄ちゃんにね、書き下ろしていただきました「chewy chewy」という楽曲になります。はい、この新曲「chewy chewy」はですね、この配信の後にMVが8時50分からプレミア公開、24時に先行リリース予定です！
nqrse-san, my big bro, wrote a song for me called "chewy chewy." It will premiere at 8:50 PM and release early at midnight!
やっぱね、ナールセさんといたらね、ラップじゃないですか！で、この曲にラップがあるのかどうなのかっていうのは、まあこの後歌いますから、楽しみにしていて欲しいです。
If you're with nqrse-san, it's rap! So I hope you look forward to whether there's rap in this song.
え、MVに関してはですね、普段ちょっとやったことない動きをね、あの、ディレクターさんにこう動いてほしいとか、動いてほしいとか言われながら試行錯誤して頑張ってやったんで、ちょっと違和感もあるかもしれないけど頑張ったトワがね見れるMVに、仕上がりました！なので、この後のプレミア公開は楽しみにしといてくれればなと思います。そしてね、この後、え、ナールセさんが書き下ろしてくださった「chewy chewy」を歌いたいと思いますので、
I did movements I don't usually do through trial and error, so it turned out as an MV where you can see a hardworking Towa!
ぜひ、えー、ちょっとここで落ち着かないとね、ぜひ、えー、聴いてもらえればと思います。では「chewy chewy」！
Please listen to it. Now, "chewy chewy"!
自堕落なボーイ 切れ者のボーイ
Corrupt boy, sharp boy,
耳貸しな coast to coast 飛ばす 音
Lend me your ears, coast to coast, blasting sounds,
ハイカラなガール 高飛車なガール
Trendy girl, haughty girl,
針落とし当然と揺らすフロア レトロ
Dropping the needle naturally shaking the floor, retro,
また錆びた鎖で縛ってを
Binding again with rusted chains,
どの道を選ぼうなんて
Which path should I choose,
黒光かよ上出来だって
even a pitch-black romance is well-done,
ドーナツペイン夢のゲーム
donut pain, a dream game—
どのハートも遠く仕掛け
every heart is set far away.
馬鹿にされた毒手になって
Becoming a mocked poisonous hand,
自由すらもう消し去っていいよ
it's fine to erase even freedom.
「前を」とつつむ幻想よ
The illusion wrapping around saying "Look ahead"
溺れるのに掴めない
Even though I'm drowning, I can't grasp it,
水のように透き通るためなら
if it's to become transparent like water.
この幸せのようにはしゃげ
Frolic like this happiness—
忘れかけてたも
What I had begun to forget,
忘れてきた知るよる闇
the night I came to know, forgetting it,
頭に響く足跡は
the footsteps echoing in my head—
迷いもなく振り向かない
without hesitation, I won't look back.
始まりの目に映る世界
The world reflected in my starting eyes,
くだらない いつも笑って
how foolish, always smiling—
惑わせ望む葛藤に焦がれ
yearning for the conflict that seduces and desires,
目に映れ fade out
fading out in my eyes.
くだらない いつも笑って
How foolish, always smiling—
火を灯せ follow, follow
lighting the fire, follow, follow.
探して 疑って
Searching, doubting,
お好きなの catch me
whatever you like, catch me,
理由くれ baby
give me a reason, baby.
もぐもぐもぐもぐ chewy chewy
Munching, munching, munching, munching, chewy chewy,
手を合わせる何度もかっぽ
putting hands together, countless times wide open,
詰まったメロウ
jammed mellow.
隠されたまま痛いは
Remaining hidden, it hurts—
退屈なのは浅い会話
what's boring is shallow conversation.
傷は家のまんま痛いは
Remaining at home, the wounds hurt—
消えちゃいてな
as if they'll disappear.
まずはじめて見ないふり
First, pretending not to see,
帰る場所はどこだったっけ
where was the place I return to?
真っさらで傷一つね
Brand new, not a single scratch,
囲い合いたい君今
the you I want to surround right now
を生きるのは
is living it.
誇れるもまいで目配せ
Even if proud, exchanging glances,
を得て戸惑いしゃおち捕まえて
catching the confusion.
惑わす黒子は豹変する
The misleading mole suddenly transforms,
スポットは網羅しだ全部
illuminating all the spotlights.
具体的な美食はurger
Concrete delicacies are vulgar—
この傷跡がすかしてdazzle
these scars transparently dazzle.
大したことないと思うなら
If you think it's no big deal,
受け止めてよ holopain
catch it, holopain!
くだらない いつも笑って
How foolish, always smiling—
火を灯せ follow, follow
lighting the fire, follow, follow.
探して 疑って
Searching, doubting,
お好きなの catch me
whatever you like, catch me,
理由くれ baby
give me a reason, baby.
くだらない いつも笑って
How foolish, always smiling—
火を灯せ follow, follow
lighting the fire, follow, follow.
探して 疑って
Searching, doubting,
お好きなの catch me
whatever you like, catch me,
理由くれ baby
give me a reason, baby.
どうしたい？でも燃え尽きた
What do you want? But burnt out,
刺し伸べないでんだ
don't reach out.
甘えちゃうわ、さなば感じての自分よ
I'll act spoiled, feeling like my true self.
あなたを縛る時代よ
It's an era that binds you—
don't care, just don't care,この情熱を
don't care, just don't care about this passion.
くだらない いつも笑って
How foolish, always smiling—
火を灯せ follow, follow
lighting the fire, follow, follow.
探して 疑って
Searching, doubting,
お好きなの catch me
whatever you like, catch me,
理由くれ baby
give me a reason, baby.
くだらない いつも笑って
How foolish, always smiling—
火を灯せ follow, follow
lighting the fire, follow, follow.
探して 疑って
Searching, doubting,
お好きなの catch me
whatever you like, catch me,
理由くれ baby
give me a reason, baby.
もぐもぐもぐもぐ chewy chewy
Munching, munching, munching, munching, chewy chewy,
munching, munching, munching, munching, chewy chewy.
手を合わせる何度もかっぽ
Putting hands together, countless times wide open,
詰まったメロウ
jammed mellow.
この道はどこへ続いているのだろう？
Where does this path lead?
目の前に
Right before my eyes,
無数に
countless
別れた
branching
可能性が広がっている。
possibilities are spreading out.
ワタシは、私であるために
So that I can be myself,
自分を縛る言葉は捨てて、広がっていくのは
casting off words that bind me, what spreads out
私だけの、まだ知らない光。
is my own light, still unknown.
10.29 ARIAKE ARENA
Tokoyami Towa 2nd Live SHINier
進め。輝き溢れる、光の先へ。
Advance. Toward the light overflowing with radiance.
はい！
Hi!
皆さん、なんと…えーと、常闇トワのセカンド…そのライブが…
Everyone... guess what? Um, Tokoyami Towa's second... live...
決定しました――！やった――！うお――！きたぞ――！
has been decided! Yay! Whoa! It's here!
ついに…公開された…！
It's finally... been announced...!
よかった…！
I'm so glad...!
ここまで色々あったんですけれども、まだここが始まり…なんだけど、頑張りますからね！
A lot has happened up to here, but this is still just the beginning... yet I'll do my best!
どうでした？びっくりしました？
How was it? Were you surprised?
ありがとう！ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you so much! Thank you!
泣きそう…分かる？
I'm about to cry... You know?
ちょっと…泣きそうなの分かりますわ。一緒。でも…とっときましょう。それは。
I understand why I look like I'm about to cry. Same here. But... let's save that. For later.
皆さん…今じゃないわ。とっとこう、本番までに！
Everyone... not right now. Let's save it for the real show!
えー、ということで、今回のね、ライブタイトルは常闇トワセカンドライブ SHINier
Uh, so, the live title this time is Tokoyami Towa 2nd Live "SHINier".
SHINierです。
It's SHINier.
え、こちらなんですけど、さっき初売、え、発表したアルバムのねタイトル、芯に繋がってるんですよね。
The title of the album we announced just earlier is connected to our "core."
このね、え、アルバムなんですけれども、いろいろな芯が入っているアルバムとなってまして、
This album features various kinds of cores,
その、えー、芯に沿って今回の、え、ライブタイトルも、え、SHINierというふうに、え、付けさせていただきました。
and in alignment with that, we've titled this live tour "SHINier."
ファーストライブのね、え、常闇よりも、え、もっと輝いて、かっこいい、
Shining even brighter and looking cooler than my first live,
え、無限大の可能性をみんなにお届けするので、ぜひ見に来てくれたらなと思います。
I'll be delivering infinite possibilities to everyone, so I hope you'll come watch.
はい、じゃそしてキービジュアル見てみましょう！
Right, now let's check out the key visual!
はい、どうですか！こちらね、え、アルバムのジャケット写真描いていただいた花芽さんにね、え、キービジュアルも一緒に描いていただきました。めっちゃかっこいいよね！
How is it? Hanasa-san, who illustrated the album jacket, also drew this key visual for us. Isn't it super cool?
さっきのちょっと黒い、暗い感じだったんだけど、こっちらはね、光が見えるような感じで、え、進んでいくような、え、前にいけるような明るさを、え、演出してもらいましたね。
While the previous one had a darker, moodier feel, this one gives off a sense of light, evoking progress and moving forward into brightness.
すごいもうクールでかっこいい、けどみたいな感じを出せたらと思っておりまして、衣装もお気に入りです。当日楽しみです。
I wanted to give it a cool yet edgy vibe, and I really love the outfit too. I'm so looking forward to the day of the show.
そして、え、今回のハッシュタグはライブ・アルバムどちらも共通で、え、ハッシュタグ#シャープ常闇、あ、常闇だって、常闇自分野名前噛むってすごくない？
Also, the hashtag for both the live and album is `#SharpTokoyami`—wait, Tokoyami? Isn't it amazing to bite into your own name?
え、#シャープ常闇とはセカンドです。もう帰りたい！ねえ、笑いすぎだから！
Uh, `#SharpTokoyami` is the second one. I wanna go home! Hey, you're laughing too much!
え、じゃ今日から改めまして常闇になりますのでよろしくお願いいたします。え、皆さんいっぱいねポストしてくれたらなと思います。
Well, starting today I'm officially Tokoyami again, so please treat me well. I hope you'll post lots about it!
そして、え、皆さんお待ちかねチケット情報です！
And now, everyone's been waiting for this: ticket info!
本当に耳が学なるんだけど、え、会場はなんと、え、有明アリーナ、有明アリーナです！はい。
My ears are ringing just thinking about it, but the venue is... Ariake Arena! Yes!
え、前回よりもね、もう、すごいな、何倍？3倍？2.5倍？ぐらいね、え、会場も広くなって、もう前回あんなに緊張して最初震えてたのに、
Compared to last time, the venue is... how many times bigger? 3 times? 2.5 times? It's so much larger, and even though I was trembling and shaking with nerves last time,
あの、だ、だ、だ、大丈夫かなっていう心配で、
I was so worried about whether I'd be okay...
でも、あの、全然実感わかなかったんですけど、この今この配信してちょっと実感わいてきて、プルプルしてきました。ドキドキしてます。でも頑張ります。
But I couldn't really feel it at first. Doing this stream right now has made it hit me, and I'm trembling. My heart is pounding, but I'll do my best!
え、チケットはSS席、S席、A席、B席の4種席です。
Tickets come in 4 types: SS, S, A, and B seats.
え、こちらのね、SS席が気になってると思うんですけど、SS席というのは、え、SHINierサポーターの略で、え、SHINierはトワのことで、そのサポーターは皆様のことなんですよね！はい。
I'm sure you're curious about SS seats. "SS" stands for "SHINier Supporter"—"SHINier" refers to Towa, and "Supporters" refers to all of you! Yes.
そしてね、SS席には特典でブレスレットライトがついてきます！ちょっとお高いかもしれないんですけども、このね席とかねブレスレットライトがついてくる点を考えると、もう目の前で爆音で聞いて欲しいなっていう感じなんですけどね。
And SS seats come with a special bracelet light! It might be a bit pricey, but considering you get this seat and the bracelet light, I really want you to experience the booming sound right in front of you.
え、ライブロゴやねタイトルが入っている特別仕様で、え、紫色のおとめががマグネットになっていて、付け外しができるようになっております。
It's a special design featuring the live logo and title, with a purple clasp that is magnetic and detachable.
点灯カラーは白色になっておりまして、SS席のサポーターの皆様まはこれで会場全体を輝かきらきらきらきらしていただければなと思います。
The lit color is white, and I hope all our SS Supporter members will use this to make the entire venue sparkle and shine brilliantly.
あの、すっごいいっぱいあるからさ、あの、頑張ってね今。
There are so many of them, so I'm working hard right now!
え、じゃあね、気になる各座席のエリアマップ見てみましょう。どんなもんなんじゃいということで、はい。
Now let's check out the seat map for each area to see what it looks like. Here we go!
そうなんです、SS席はなんとステージのど真ん中にあります！で、その周りをS席、え、A席、B席というふうに、え、周りを囲んでいる形ですね。
That's right, SS seats are right in the dead center of the stage! And surrounding that are S, A, and B seats.
え、現チケットはこの後21時から1次抽選の申し込みが始まるので、みんな是非応募してください。
Ticket applications for the physical tickets will start from 9 PM tonight in the first lottery, so everyone please apply!
え、海外の皆様も買えますのでよろしくお願いします。オーバーシーブロー、え、シース、
Overseas fans can purchase them too, so please check it out. Overseas bro, seas...
え、みんなレッツバイ、レッツゴー、レッツゴー！はい。
Everyone, let's buy, let's go, let's go! Haha.
ということで、ま、でも現地に行けないよっていう人も大丈夫。え、配信チケットもあります。
That said, if you can't make it in person, don't worry. Streaming tickets are also available.
え、こちらもね21時から発売開始なので、え、特設サイトをチェックして見てください。
These also go on sale starting at 9 PM, so please check out the special site.
え、概要欄にも更新してくれてると、思うんですけども、リンクがありますので。
I think it's updated in the description box as well, where you'll find the link.
え、あるけど、あるけどね、常闇とはセカンドライブで検索してもサイトで出てくるので、ブックマークしておくといいかもしれません。ちょっと出るか検索してみて、ちょっと心配だから。
But hey, even if you search for "Tokoyami Towa Second Live", the site will show up, so bookmarking it might be a good idea. Try searching for it just in case, since I'm a bit worried.
はい、配信でもね、現地でも、どちらもかっこいいね、え、みんなが喜べる、喜んでくれるようなパフォーマンスを頑張っていきたいと思いますので、
Whether streaming or in person, both will be super cool, and I'll do my best to deliver a performance that makes everyone happy and excited!
頑張って走り抜けたいと思います。
I'll do my best to run through to the end!
はい、そしてここまであっという間だったんですが、今回のライブ情報はここまでになります。
Yes, and though it went by in a flash, that's all for today's live information.
あれ？なんかライブに必要なものが足りなくない？って思ったそこの眷属！
Wait a minute, don't you feel like something's missing for the live? All you kenzoku out there thinking that!
ここカメラが大変だったので、あの、あんまり動かないようにしますけども。
The camera work was tough here, so, um, I'll try not to move around too much.
ライブグッズは現在、準備中になります。
Live merchandise is currently in preparation.
え、またね、え、別の日にね、ライブグッズを発表する枠も取りたいと思いますから、お楽しみに待っていてください。
I'll also host another stream to reveal the live goods on a different day, so please look forward to it.
ちょきんのタイムだからね！いい？みんな、ちょきんタイム。
It's savings time, right?! Alright everyone, savings time.
と、思いきや！ここまでがライブの告知で、ちょきんタイムって言ったんだけど、ここからはちょきんしないで欲しいタイムです。
Or so you thought! That was the live announcement and I said savings time, but from here on is the time I'd rather you didn't save.
え、常闇トワ誕生日記念2025のグッズ発売告知となりまーす。
Um, it's the announcement for Tokoyami Towa's Birthday Celebration 2025 merchandise!
まあ、見てください、こちら。
Well, take a look at this.
やったー！ルルドママにイラスト描いてもらっちゃいましたー！ママありがとう！
Yay! Rurudo-mama drew illustrations for me! Thank you, Mama!
かわいいよね。
Ain't she cute?
はい、詳細はね、みんなで見いこうと思います。こちら。
Yes, let's check out the details together. Here.
じゃじゃん。そうこれママに描いてもらった、えーごシックな部屋の撮影のとわちゃん。
Ta-da! So this is Towa-chan in a gothic room photoshoot drawn by Mama.
で、ちょっとルルドママの若干の聖壁がどこかに詰まってるんで、どこか当ててくださいね。
And, well, rurudo-mama's mild fetishes are packed in somewhere, so try to guess where!
はい、そしてこちら。ビッグタオル！ミライム先生に描いていただきました。ライム先生いつもありがとう！
Yes, and here. Big towel! Illustrated by Mr.Lime-sensei. Lime-sensei, thank you as always!
このね、配信のサムネも描いてくれてました。ありがとういつも。昔からずっと描いてくださってる先生です。
He also drew this stream's thumbnail. Thank you always. He's a teacher who has been drawing for me for a long time.
はい、こちらもビッグサイズのタオル。ぜひ使っていたければなと思います。
Yes, this is also a big-sized towel. I hope you'll use it.
続いては、こちら。じゃん！トワ様とお出かけぬいぐるみキーホルダー。
Next is this. Ta-da! Towa-sama Outing Plushie Keychain.
これはですね、やっぱトワちゃんね、あの結構毎月トワベルっていうのでみんながトワのぬいぐるみと一緒に結構旅行してくれて、それをあの行った気持ちになる配信があるんですけども、
This is, well, every month there's a stream called 'Towabell' where everyone travels around with Towa's plushie, and there are streams where I feel like I'm traveling along with you.
やっぱ私服でね、ちょっとま、デートとしてやってもいいっていう意味を込めて私服のミニチュアサイズというか持ち運びできるようなお出かけぬいぐるみキーホルダーを作らせていただきましたので、また買って届いたら、いっぱいね投稿してくれたらなと思います。
So I wanted to make an outing plushie keychain in miniature casual wear—meaning you can take it on a 'date' with you—in a portable miniature size. So I hope you'll buy it, get it, and post lots of pictures!
はい、そしてこちら。眷属メタルキーホルダー。
Yes, and this. Kenzoku Metal Keychain.
え、かわいいピピと、あとトワはやっぱりね、え、歌ももちろん大好きなんですけども、ゲームもやっぱりすごく好き。
Cute Pipi, and of course Towa loves singing, but I also really love games.
なんで、えー、そのね、イメージをこちらに詰め込んでいただきました。かわいいでしょ、キーホルダー。最近トワね、いろんなところにキーホルダーをじゃらじゃら付けるのにハマってるんで作ってみました。よろしくお願いします。
So I packed that image into this. Isn't it cute, the keychain? Lately Towa's been into jingling keychains everywhere, so I made this. Please look forward to it.
フルセットの、えー、購入特典もございますので見てみましょう。
There's also a purchase bonus for the full set, so let's take a look.
はい、ルルドママの、えーちょっとペロみたいな表情差分があるトワちゃんの、えー、箔せ、箔せじゃねわ、箔押し複製サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードがついてきまーす。
Yes, rurudo-mama's foil-stamped replica signed cheki-style bromide card of Towa-chan with a slightly 'peropero' expression variation comes with it!
はい、フルセット買うとついてくるんだよ、これが。
Yes, if you buy the full set, this comes with it.
でもね、そしてね、しかもね、なんともう一個付いてきちゃうの。こちら。
But wait, and what's more, amazingly another one comes with it. Here.
戻ってね。あ、これだった、ごめん。あ、あれこれか。フルセットはこれ。はい、これ。1、2、3、4、5。これね、これが付いてきて、で、これ。これが付いてくる。次。
Let's go back. Ah, this was it, sorry. Ah, is it this? The full set is this. Yes, this. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5. This, this comes with it, and this. This comes next.
これこれこれこれ！もう、オートモシしながらこれ。これが付いてきます。えーカードが付いてきますよ。ホロライブ公式カードゲームで使用できるカードが1枚付いてきまーす、トゥーテクパート。
This, this, this, this! While ad-libbing, this. This comes with it. A card comes with it! A card usable in the Hololive Official Card Game comes with one—Towa tech part!
え、カードはねホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップでご購入された方のみ対象となっております。特典に付くのは推しをアピールできるキーカード、オシホロメンカードです。カードの詳細や遊び方についてはホームページで確認しやがれ！
Um, the cards are only available to those who purchase from the Hololive Production Official Shop. The bonus includes key cards to show off your oshi, oshi holomember cards. Check the homepage for details on the cards and how to play!
てことで以上常闇トワ誕生日記念グッズの情報でしたー。
So that was all the information on Tokoyami Towa's Birthday Celebration merchandise.
みんな買ってね。これで素敵なMV作るんだから買ってくれないといいの作れないから。よろしくお願いします。
Everyone buy it! I'm going to make a wonderful MV with this, so if you don't buy it, I can't make a good one. Please support me!
はい、そして、そして先ほどお伝えしたセカンドアルバム『G.L.A.M.』がホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップでの発売が先行して開始しております！
Yes, and earlier I mentioned my 2nd album 'G.L.A.M.', which is now available for pre-order starting exclusively at the Hololive Production Official Shop!
はい、たぶん、あの配信画面の下に入れてきた購入ボタンから発売ページに飛べるようになっていると思うんですけども、皆さん押せるようになりました？
Yes, I think you can jump to the sales page from the purchase button put under the stream screen, but were you able to press it?
あの、もしなかったらね、更新して、おねがいいたします。更新してください。
Um, if not, please refresh, please. Please refresh.
はい、え、購入ボタンをクリックする前に注意事項なのですが、セカンドアルバムとそれ以外のものを同じカードで購入していただいた場合に、発売日の10月8日までに発送が行えない可能性があるの気をつけてください。
Yes, um, before clicking the purchase button, here are some notes: if you purchase the 2nd album and other items in the same cart, shipment might not happen by the release date of October 8th, so please be careful.
セカンドアルバム単体での購入なら大丈夫です。ありがとう！買った人ありがとう、ありがとね！
Purchasing the 2nd album by itself is fine. Thank you! Thanks to everyone who bought it, thank you!
ま、この後9時からになりますからね。
Well, it starts at 9:00 after this,
ありが……応援してくれてありがとー！
so thank you for supporting me!
はい、そしてもうあと少し、この後8時50分、
And at 8:50 just a little while from now,
チュイチュイのMVプレミア公開がありまして、
the "Chui Chui" MV premiere will be held,
え、9時からライブチケットの発売がございます。
and live tickets go on sale at 9:00.
ということで、今日は1時間は長くなくてちょっと短いんですけれども、
So today's stream is a bit short,
こんな感じでまた後日配信すると思うので、
but I'll be streaming again later,
是非また遊びに来てください！
so please come hang out again!
はい、では皆さん、この後チュイチュイここにいたらすぐ消えるんで、
If you're waiting for "Chui Chui" here,
かっこいいMV消えるんで、
the cool MV will disappear quickly,
ここに待機して少々お待ちを！ということで、
so please stand by and wait a moment!
今日はありがとー！いっぱいポストしてねー！
Thank you today! Post a lot, okay!
駆け足になっちゃった。またねー！
That felt a bit rushed. See you later!